# **Ahmad Samim Qeyam**

Frontend Web Developer (JavaScript, React, js, Redux, HTML, CSS) During my three years of professional work experience, I have built several high-impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations. I am skilled in designing, developing, and testing web-based applications and databases incorporating a range of technologies. Currently, I am aspiring to combine my background with my strong technical skills to excel as a Frontend Developer.

203 Heron Drive
Pittsburg, CA 94565
United States
(925)489-8605
ahmad.qeyam@gmail.com
LinkedIn/ahmad-samim-qeyam
Portfolio
GitHub/qeyamsamim

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Frontend Web Developer** - Technical School of Innovation AUCA, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan. — *OCT 2021 - JUN 2023* 

- Managed web development projects from initial design through completion, optimizing all cross-browser and multi-platform compatibility.
- Worked closely with the backend development team and clients to meet project requirements, goals, and desired functionality.
- Conducted training for clients to handle website content management systems.

**Frontend Web Developer** - Fanoos Accounting Services, Kabul, Afghanistan. — *JUN 2021 - AUG 2021* 

- Built two Angular applications for the company; the first one facilitates the training and workshop management, and the second application automates payroll-related tasks.
- Developed a comprehensive user and developer documentation for both of the systems.
- Enhanced and maintained the existing website of the company, which led to an increase of 37% in user engagement.

**Full Stack Web Developer** - Civil Society and Human Rights Network, Kabul, Afghanistan. — *JUN 2020 - MAY 2021* 

- Performed full website migration from PHP to JavaScript. I used Angular for frontend and Node.js for backend, and deployed the application to AWS.
- Designed a database schema and developed a local MySQL database according to the organization's needs.

# **EDUCATION**

**American University of Central Asia**, Master of Arts in Business Administration. SEP 2021 – May 2023

**American University of Central Asia**, Bachelor of Software Engineering. SEP 2016 - MAY 2020

Received 2 Academic Excellence Awards, and graduated in the top 5% of my class with a GPA: 3.78/4.0.

#### **PROJECTS COMPLETED**

- Fitness Website 2023
- Ecommerce Website 2022
- Fanoos Training Management System 2021
- Fanoos Payroll Management System 2021
- Del Colosseo Web Application 2021
- SportsKG Web Application 2020

#### **STACK**

**Proficient:** JavaScript, React.js, Angular, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, REST API, Unit & E2E Testing, GitHub.

Familiar: Python, Web3.js, D3.js, AWS

## **AWARDS**

Al Hackathon (2020), AUCA -My team received 2nd rank out of 15 teams.

Database Principles Course 2018) - Built school management system. Ranked 1st in the class. Received 2nd place in the regional competition.

# **LANGUAGES**

Persian native
English C2, fluent
Russian B1, intermediate
German A2, beginner

#### **INTERESTS**

Design, Artificial Intelligence, Gaming, Reading, Creative Writing, Fitness, Soccer